<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on Marshall Lab</title>
    <link>/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on Marshall Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;**Marshall BOOM Lab**</title>
      <link>/home/hero/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/hero/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Biofilm Origins, Oecology, and Metabolism Exploring the extraordinary metabolic versatility of the microbes in and around us </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/about/</guid>
      <description>Research Overview My research program addresses two grand challenges in science: antimicrobial resistance and quantifying global biogeochemical cycling. In the first, I am interested in how diversity and metabolic changes in biofilms contribute to the alarming and expanding problem of antibiotic resistance. In the second, I study anaerobic metabolisms associated with biogeochemical cycles as a biotechnological and ecological source of innovation. Traditionally these disciplines don’t intersect. I would argue, however, that microbial ecology and evolution mediated by metabolic feedback lie at the core of each.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/home/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/home/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/publications/</guid>
      <description>Google Scholar Page
 Scribner MR, Santos-Lopez A, Marshall CW, Deitrick C, Cooper VS. Parallel evolution of tobramycin resistance across species and environments. bioRxiv. 2019. https://doi.org/10.1101/758979.
 Santos-Lopez* A, Marshall* CW, Scribner MR, Snyder DJ, Cooper VS. Evolutionary Pathways to Antibiotic Resistance are Dependent Upon Environmental Structure and Bacterial Lifestyle. eLife. 2019. eLife 2019;8:e47612.
 Lopez S, Martin JM, Johnson M, Kurs-Lasky Horne WT, Marshall CW, Cooper VS, Williams JV, Shaikh N.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</title>
      <link>/home/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/talks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/home/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Experimental Microbiology. Marquette University. Undergraduate. Fall 2019. BIO 4802.
Comprehensive Microbiology. University of Pittsburgh. Graduate level. Spring 2018 &amp;amp; Spring 2019. 2184 MSMI 1100.
Pseudomonas and Friends Journal Club. University of Pittsburgh.
Applied and Environmental Microbiology. Duquesne University. Graduate and Undergraduate level. Spring 2017. ENVI 497&amp;frasl;597 BIO 432W/532.
The Microbiome and Health. Undergraduate level. Univeristy of Chicago. Spring 2015. BIOS 15123.
General Microbiology. Graduate and Undergraduate level. College of Charleston. 2009 – 2011.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/home/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>