<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Homes on Marshall Lab</title>
    <link>/home/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Homes on Marshall Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/home/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;**Welcome to the BOOM**</title>
      <link>/home/hero/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/hero/</guid>
      <description>&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Biofilm Origins, Oecology, and Metabolism Exploring the extraordinary metabolic versatility of the microbes in and around us </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/home/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/about/</guid>
      <description>Biography Chris Marshall is a research assistant professor in the Department of Microbiology and Molecular Genetics at the University of Pittsburgh. His research interests include the evolution of antimicrobial resistance, eco-evolutionary dynamics, environmental microbiology, bioremediation, and bioelectrochemistry. Chris did his PhD in Hal May&amp;rsquo;s lab at MUSC studying extracellular electron transfer pathways in Gram positive bacteria powering microbial fuel cells and microbial electrosynthesis systems. Following his Phd, Chris won the prestigious Argonne Director&amp;rsquo;s Fellowship and worked with Ken Kemner and Jack Gilbert at Argonne National Laboratory and University of Chicago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/home/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/publications/</guid>
      <description>Google Scholar Page
 Melvin J, Gaston J, Phillips S, Springer M, Marshall CW, Shanks R, Bomberger J. Pseudomonas aeruginosa Contact-Dependent Growth Inhibition Plays a Dual Role in Host-Pathogen Interactions. 2017. mSphere. 2 (6). e00336-17.
 Marshall CW, DE Ross, KM Handley, PB Weisenhorn, CS Henry, JA Gilbert, HD May, RS Norman. Metabolic Reconstruction and Modeling Microbial Electrosynthesis. 2017. Scientific Reports. 10.1038/s41598-017-08877-z (SREP-17-14408).
 Ross DE, Marshall CW, May HD, Norman RS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent &amp; Upcoming Talks</title>
      <link>/home/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/talks/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/home/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/projects/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/home/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/teaching/</guid>
      <description>Comprehensive Microbiology. University of Pittsburgh. Graduate level. Spring 2018. 2184 MSMI 1100.
Pseudomonas and Friends Journal Club. University of Pittsburgh.
Applied and Environmental Microbiology. Duquesne University. Graduate and Undergraduate level. Spring 2017. ENVI 497&amp;frasl;597 BIO 432W/532.
The Microbiome and Health. Undergraduate level. Univeristy of Chicago. Spring 2015. BIOS 15123.
General Microbiology. Graduate and Undergraduate level. College of Charleston. 2009 – 2011. Bio 310 / 320.
Environmental Microbiology. Graduate level. MUSC. Spring 2010 - 2012.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/home/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>